<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Setup and Installation on Newspaper Curation App</title>
    <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Setup and Installation on Newspaper Curation App</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Services and Apps</title>
      <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/services/</guid>
      <description>You should at least understand everything in this document at a high level before moving on to the setup/installation documents, as the NCA suite is a set of tools, not a single application that does it all.
Overview NCA has two key services which you&amp;rsquo;ll have to run, in addition to the rest of the external services (such as an IIIF server, MySQL / MariaDB, and Apach)
If you&amp;rsquo;re doing a manual installation rather than container-based, you are strongly advised to look at the docker files - they make it clear precisely how the stack should be set up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Setup</title>
      <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/server-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/server-setup/</guid>
      <description>Human Requirements Unfortunately, this process is still technical enough that you will need a devops person to at least get the system set up for processing. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need people who can reorder PDF pages (if necessary) as well as people who can enter and review newspaper issue metadata.
Somebody will want to monitor the output from the various automated processes, such as QCing generated batches on a staging server prior to loading in production, as there is still a great deal of room for human error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installation</title>
      <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/installation/</guid>
      <description>Development If you&amp;rsquo;re developing on NCA, installation will differ from standing up a production server. Please see our Development Guide.
Preliminary Setup Manual installation has several prerequisites:
 Go and some dependencies (see below) Poppler Utils for PDF processing OpenJPEG 2 + command-line tools for JP2 generation  The command-line tools will probably need to be manually compiled to support converting PNG files. Most distributions of Linux don&amp;rsquo;t have this by default, hence the need to manually compile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Users</title>
      <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/user-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/user-setup/</guid>
      <description>Newspaper Curation App - User Setup First-time Setup Once the applications are installed and configured, start the NCA server in debug mode:
./bin/server -c ./settings --debug  This lets you fake an admin login via http://your.site/users?debuguser=admin. You can then set up other users as necessary. Once you have Apache set up to do the authentication, you should never run in debug mode on production servers.
For development use, docker-compose.override.yml-example is already set up to run in debug mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Onboarding A Publisher</title>
      <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/creating-publishers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/setup/creating-publishers/</guid>
      <description>Creating a publisher in NCA, at least for UO, requires several manual processes take place:
 Add a title to NCA with sftp credential information. If necessary, import the title to your ONI site (for example, oregonnews.uoregon.edu).  See Adding Titles for details   Add a user to the sftp server  At UO, we have an internal sftp script at /usr/local/scripts/addsftpuser.sh. e.g., /usr/local/scripts/addsftpuser.sh &amp;quot;newpublisher&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Pas$w0rd&amp;quot;   Symlink the sftp server&amp;rsquo;s location so NCA can see it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
