<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NCA Terms, Specs, and Information on Newspaper Curation App</title>
    <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/specs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NCA Terms, Specs, and Information on Newspaper Curation App</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/specs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/specs/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/specs/glossary/</guid>
      <description>NDNP / Newspaper Catalogers These are terms I&amp;rsquo;m trying to use properly, but which I sometimes still mess up. Don&amp;rsquo;t let that happen to you!
Title: A distinct newspaper title, such as The Daily Prophet. All titles will have a unique LCCN. LCCN: Library of Congress Control Number: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Library_of_Congress_Control_Number. In terms of NCA (and ONI and chronam), this uniquely identifies a newspaper title. Issue: A single published issue of a newspaper title, such as the April 20th edition of The Daily Prophet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uploads: Folder and File Specs</title>
      <link>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/specs/upload-specs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uoregon-libraries.github.io/newspaper-curation-app/specs/upload-specs/</guid>
      <description>Uploads: Folder and File Specs Publishers (or in-house scanners) who upload issues must adhere to very strict structures for issue organization.
Born-Digital (PDFs uploaded via SFTP) The folder structure tells us the newspaper title and issue date. e.g., /mnt/news/sftp/sftpuser/2018-01-02 would mean the January 2nd, 2018 edition of title whose SFTP login is &amp;ldquo;sftpuser&amp;rdquo;.
The issue should contain PDFs and nothing else. Publishers should never upload tertiary files. Ideally, publishers should upload one PDF for the entire issue, with pages in the order they wish to see on the ONI site, as that reduces (or eliminates) the need to have anybody reviewing these issues&amp;rsquo; pages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
